    <article id="manual"
             data-sblg-article="1"
             data-sblg-set-title="Profanity, a console based XMPP client - Helping Out"
             data-sblg-set-subtitle="Helping Out">
        <section>
            <h3>Contents</h3>
            
            <ul>
                <li><a href="#use-profanity">Use Profanity</a></li>
                <li><a href="#website-help">Help with the website</a></li>
                <li><a href="#contribute-code">Contribute code</a></li>
                <li><a href="#donate">Donate</a></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <a name="use-profanity"></a>
            <h3>Use Profanity</h3>
            
            <p>The easiest way you can help out is just by using Profanity and sending any feedback you have to the <a id="link-mailinglist" href="https://lists.notraces.net/mailman/listinfo/profanity" target="_blank">mailing list</a>.
            Any feedback is welcome, although please keep it polite, and refrain from using profanity (pun intended).</p>
            <p>See <a href="issues.html">Reporting issues</a> for information on where and how to report issues, and how to supply logs/debug information.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <a name="website-help"></a>
            <h3>Help with the website</h3>
            
            <p>The website often has small errors or omissions in documentation etc. The website source is also <a id="link-websitesource" href="https://github.com/profanity-im/profanity-im.github.io" target="_blank">available at github</a> so feel free to send pull requests there.</p>
            <p>We're always interested to hear about profanity being used in different environments, and if you have any screenshots, we'd be happy to post them at the website.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <a name="contribute-code"></a>
            <h3>Contribute code</h3>
            
            <p>Code contributions are always very welcome. From the small (spelling fixes) to the large (new XMPP features).</p>
            <p>If you would like to get involved, you can submit a pull request, or if you just want to get involved but don't know how, email jubalh@iodoru.org.</p>
            <p>Also make sure to read the <a href="https://github.com/profanity-im/profanity/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md">CONTRIBUTING</a> document on GitHub.</p>
			<p>To find a first issue to work on check out the various repositories:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><a href="https://github.com/profanity-im/profanity">Profanity</a></li>
				<li><a href="https://github.com/profanity-im/profanity-im.github.io">Website</a></li>
				<li><a href="https://github.com/profanity-im/profanity-plugins">Plugins</a></li>
			</ul>
			<p>Click on the tab called <b>Issues</b> in the repository on GitHub and go through them until you find something that interests you.</p>
			<p>We also tag our issues. So you can easily see if something is a bug or a feature request. Or which part of the code the issue is about, like e.g. <b>UI</b>.</p>
			<p>Especially check out the issues tagged as <a href="https://github.com/profanity-im/profanity/issues?q=is%3Aissue%20state%3Aopen%20label%3A%22help%20wanted%22">help wanted</a>.</p>
			<p>You can also check out the milestones where we plan which issues should be solved for certain milestones/releases. The milestone called <a href="https://github.com/profanity-im/profanity/issues?q=is%3Aissue%20state%3Aopen%20milestone%3Anext">next</a> contains the issues for the next release.</p>
			<p>People find it often the easiest to work on a bug that affects them personally. Or to implement a feature that they want to have. So think about what you want and need. You can also join our MUC to get help about getting started with development on Profanity</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <a name="donate"></a>
            <h3>Donate</h3>

            <p>Yes, the rumors are true. Developers also have to eat. They also have limited time.</p>
            <p>And yet some of them decide to use their free time to develop free software.</p>
            <p>If you want to say "Thank You", please consider <a href="donate.html">donating</a>.</p>
        </section>
    </article>
