<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>profanity</title>
    <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/authors/debxwoody/</link>
    <description>Recent content on profanity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:07:30 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/authors/debxwoody/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Profanity and OpenPGP for XMPP (OX)</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/openpgp-for-xmpp-ox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:07:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/openpgp-for-xmpp-ox/</guid>
      <description>We have been to implement OX in profanity. OX is XEP-0374: OpenPGP for XMPP Instant Messaging which may replace XEP-0027: Current Jabber OpenPGP Usage.
It is part of Profanity since version 0.10 but got some fixes since then.
Feel free to try and test the implementation. Let us know, if you have some issues and support the development via testing and reporting bugs.
How does it works? There are some parts which will be done directly with GnuPG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention, attention!</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/attention-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 15:07:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/attention-attention/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks,
we have implemented an attention flag in profanity.
The attention flag can be used to mark chats and groupchats where you would like to pay particular attention.
This is only available on master, but will be in the next release (0.11.0).
How it works Open the chat or groupchat window and press shortcut ALT+F. Profanity will display a line to inform you when the attention flag has been activated and deactivated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OMEMO</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/omemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 17:14:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/omemo/</guid>
      <description>OMEMO with profanity.
Hello OMEMO! OMEMO needs crytographic materials. You can generated this crytographic materials via /omemo gen. If you have more than one device, make sure you are trusting your other devices. Check your fingerprints via /omemo fingerprint. You may wont trust all your devices:
/omemo trust &amp;lt;Your XMPP-ID&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Your fingerpint&amp;gt; Check the fingerprint of your buddy. List the fingerprints of your buddy via
/omemo fingerprint &amp;lt;XMPP-ID of your buddy&amp;gt; Check the fingerprints with you buddy over a secure medium (phone or singed OpenPGP message) and trust the buddy&amp;rsquo;s fingerprint via the command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run profanity instances within tmux</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/how-to-run-profanity-instances-within-tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 14:49:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/how-to-run-profanity-instances-within-tmux/</guid>
      <description>If you have more than one XMPP account, you may run one profanity process per account. For example profanity -a AccountName.
It&amp;rsquo;s possible to start a tmux session with one window for each profanity instance.
Create a tmux configuration file, e.g. in ~/.config/tmux.
mkdir ~/.config/tmux touch ~/.config/tmux/profanity.conf  Within the configuration file, you create a tmux session named Profanity. Followed by one window per XMPP Account. Each window will run a profanity followed by -a accountname.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
