<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on profanity</title>
    <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on profanity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:07:30 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Profanity and OpenPGP for XMPP (OX)</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/openpgp-for-xmpp-ox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:07:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/openpgp-for-xmpp-ox/</guid>
      <description>We have been to implement OX in profanity. OX is XEP-0374: OpenPGP for XMPP Instant Messaging which may replace XEP-0027: Current Jabber OpenPGP Usage.
It is part of Profanity since version 0.10 but got some fixes since then.
Feel free to try and test the implementation. Let us know, if you have some issues and support the development via testing and reporting bugs.
How does it works? There are some parts which will be done directly with GnuPG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profanity on Pinephone</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/profanity-on-pinephone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 20:47:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/profanity-on-pinephone/</guid>
      <description>Hi all,
So far, in my pinephone I used mainly GUI applications, because I was using a touch screen. Terminal applications are not user-friendly when it comes to one-handed operation.
I tested different distributions on my pinephone (mobian, manjaro, archarm), but usually most based on Phosh. In my opinion it is currently the best mobile graphics environment and stable as well.
In Phosh I tested few xmpp clients:
 the default application installed with Phosh is chatty, a combine that supports sms / mms / xmpp (OMEMO) Dino from repo: handy Gajim  I know there are KDE plasma applications as well, but during my testing, plasma was unusable and I even gave up installing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention, attention!</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/attention-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 15:07:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/attention-attention/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks,
we have implemented an attention flag in profanity.
The attention flag can be used to mark chats and groupchats where you would like to pay particular attention.
This is only available on master, but will be in the next release (0.11.0).
How it works Open the chat or groupchat window and press shortcut ALT+F. Profanity will display a line to inform you when the attention flag has been activated and deactivated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OMEMO</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/omemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 17:14:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/omemo/</guid>
      <description>OMEMO with profanity.
Hello OMEMO! OMEMO needs crytographic materials. You can generated this crytographic materials via /omemo gen. If you have more than one device, make sure you are trusting your other devices. Check your fingerprints via /omemo fingerprint. You may wont trust all your devices:
/omemo trust &amp;lt;Your XMPP-ID&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Your fingerpint&amp;gt; Check the fingerprint of your buddy. List the fingerprints of your buddy via
/omemo fingerprint &amp;lt;XMPP-ID of your buddy&amp;gt; Check the fingerprints with you buddy over a secure medium (phone or singed OpenPGP message) and trust the buddy&amp;rsquo;s fingerprint via the command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profanity 0.9.0</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/release-090/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 14:46:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/release-090/</guid>
      <description>Four months and 350 commits after 0.8.1 we are happy to release 0.9.0.
7 people contributed code to it: pasis, wstrm, DebXWoody, toogley, pmaziere, moppman and jubalh.
Thanks to everybody who was involved, be it testing, writing documentation, updating the website or whatever you did! I also would like to express my gratitude to my sponsors mdosch and wstrm!
LMC We support XEP-0308: Last Message Correction now. Enable it with /correction on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New mailing list</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/new-mailing-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 22:50:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/new-mailing-list/</guid>
      <description>I would like to announce that thanks to toogley we have a new mailing list. You can register on https://lists.notraces.net/mailman/listinfo/profanity
The list is hosted by datenkollektiv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing a Patch via GitHub</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/contributing-a-patch-via-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 13:50:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/contributing-a-patch-via-github/</guid>
      <description>Several people mentioned in our MUC that they have problems contributing code to the Profanity repo on GitHub because &amp;ldquo;forking all the time is cumbersome&amp;rdquo;.
Let me show you an example workflow. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s cumbersome at all. I assume you have an account on GitHub and are logged in. First thing we do is fork the repo. So go to https://github.com/profanity-im/profanity and click on &amp;ldquo;Fork&amp;rdquo;. Now you should be at your fork, in my case this is: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML console in Profanity</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/xml-console-in-profanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 21:16:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/xml-console-in-profanity/</guid>
      <description>Profanity is an XMPP client that allows you to chat with friends. But one feature makes it more than just a client. The name is XML console.
It has been implemented for a long time now, but hasn&amp;rsquo;t found wide spread within Profanity community. I still believe that the XML console is unpopular because users haven&amp;rsquo;t chance to find it and to try it out. And Profanity community has a number of experts who use XMPP in their projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run profanity instances within tmux</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/how-to-run-profanity-instances-within-tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 14:49:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/how-to-run-profanity-instances-within-tmux/</guid>
      <description>If you have more than one XMPP account, you may run one profanity process per account. For example profanity -a AccountName.
It&amp;rsquo;s possible to start a tmux session with one window for each profanity instance.
Create a tmux configuration file, e.g. in ~/.config/tmux.
mkdir ~/.config/tmux touch ~/.config/tmux/profanity.conf  Within the configuration file, you create a tmux session named Profanity. Followed by one window per XMPP Account. Each window will run a profanity followed by -a accountname.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Message Correction</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/lmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 11:34:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/lmc/</guid>
      <description>From 10th to 14th February 2020 we had Hackweek 19 at SUSE. Part of that time I used to finally implement the long (since 2016!) sought after Last Message Correction feature, aka XEP-0308.
See my Hackweek project and the corresponding pull request.
Usage To enable incoming and outgoing corrections users need to enable it with /correction on, see /help correction for more details.
Now we write a message to a friend /msg Martin Hey therr!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profanity 0.8.0</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/release-080/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 14:46:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/release-080/</guid>
      <description>On 2012-02-02 the first commit to Profanity was done by @boothj5. So now Profanity is already 8 years old! Happy Birthday!
As a present we release today the next version: 0.8.0! It&amp;rsquo;s released five months after 0.7.0 and has 295 commits since then.
Also more and more people contribute to Profanity&amp;rsquo;s development. A big thanks to: @paulfariello, @svensp, @aaptel, @aszlig, @mdosch, @pasis, @mzagozen, @quite, @weiss, @Misaflo and @jubalh.
New features We got fingerprint autocompletion for the /omemo trust command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get a backtrace</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/how-to-get-a-backtrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 17:16:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/how-to-get-a-backtrace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re running profanity master it may occur that profanity crashes
with SIGSEGV or SIGABRT when new features are added. If this happens it
is helpful to provide a backtrace for the developers to find and fix the
bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will explain one possibility how to get a backtrace of profanity
(or any other TUI application)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 17:16:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://profanity-im.github.io/blog/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks! Now with the 0.8.0 release around the corner we would like to start a development blog. We hope to give you some insights here about ongoing work, our problems, goals and where you could contribute.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
